A Register of the Georgii Pavlovich Larin Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Georgii Pavlovich Larin Papers
1922-1975
2008C79
Larin, Georgii Pavlovich
3 microfilm reels (0.45 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These papers contain the correspondence of Georgii Pavlovich Larin, a Russian émigré and Cossack, who was active in China, and later emigrated to Australia. Included are various materials relating to the activities of the Bratstvo russkoi pravdy in China, a Russian émigré anti-communist secret society, such as correspondence, circulars, orders, reports, and printed matter. Of interest are also documents relating to the Russkoe obshchestvo vzaimnogo kredita (Russian Mutual Credit Corporation)
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Alternative Forms of Material Available
A portion of the collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Biography
1900 September 6 Born, Orenburg, Russia
1922 Evacuated with White Army from Vladivostok, arrived in Shanghai the same year
1933 Founded the Russian Mutual Credit Corporation
1949 Evacuated to Tubabao, Philippines Arrived in Sydney, Australia
1992 Died, Sydney, Australia
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain the correspondence of Georgii Pavlovich Larin, a Russian émigré and Cossack, who was active in China, and later emigrated to Australia. Included are various materials relating to the activities of the Bratstvo russkoi pravdy in China, a Russian émigré anti-communist secret society, such as correspondence, circulars, orders, reports, and printed matter. Of interest are also documents relating to the Russkoe obshchestvo vzaimnogo kredita (Russian Mutual Credit Corporation), on whose board of trustees Larin served from 1933 to 1943. This collection provides a valuable insight into the life of the Russian emigration in Shanghai, China.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series: Biographical file, Correspondence, Subject file, Photographs, and Oversize file
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Bratstvo russkoi pravdy.; Russians--Shanghai, China.; Russians--Tubabao, Philippines.; Photographs.
Related Material
Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Sviatoslav Varlaamovich Denisov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Ivan Alekseevich Poliakov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Archimandrite Polikarp (Gorbunov) Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Collection Contents
- Biographical file, 1922-1975 and undated. (Box 1)
  Certificates, clippings, and inventory. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Certificates, 1922-1949. (Folder 1: 1)
    Copies, includes certificates from cadet corps, cossack, and émigré organizations
  - Clippings, 1940. (Folder 1: 2)
    Includes explanatory note written by Larin in 1975
  - Inventory of archival papers, 1969-1975 and undated (Folder 1: 3)
- Correspondence, 1925-1970 and undated.
  Cards and letters, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Unidentified, 1934-1970 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Akulinin, T., 1929 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Antonii (Khrapovitskii), Metropolitan, 1935-1936 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Arkhangel'skii, Aleksei Petrovich, 1954-1955 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Balashov, A. V., 1959-1960 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Bogaevskii, A. P., 1929 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Bratstvo russkoi pravdy., See also Subject file/Bratstvo russkoi pravdy/Correspondence
    - 1931-1948 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1961-1965 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Burlin, P., 1934-1936 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Cheremshanskii, Iurii Apollonovich, 1959-1961 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Chirkov, N., 1954 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Domracheev, M., 1935-1937 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Elenevskii, A., 1940-1970 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Isaev, I., 1936 (Folder 1: 17)
  - Khorvat, Dimitrii Leonidovich, 1932-1936. (Folder 1: 18)
    Includes untitled typescript on the political power struggle in the Far East, 1932
  - Kniupfer, Georgii Mavrikievich, 1967 (Folder 1: 19)
  - Kolosova, Mariana Ivanovna, 1932-1935 (Folder 1: 20)
  - Krasnov, Nikolai N., 1957-1959 (Folder 1: 21)
  - Krasnov, Petr Nikolaevich and Lidiia Fedorovna, 1925-1948 (Folder 1: 22)
  - Purin, A. A., 1950-1959 (Folder 1: 23)
  - Romanov, Nikita Aleksandrovich, 1966 (Folder 1: 24)
  - Semenov, Grigorii Mikhailovich, 1939 (Folder 1: 25)
  - Shevchenko, David, Reverend, 1950-1963 and undated (Folder 1: 26)
  - Sokolova, Lidiia, 1936-1957 (Folder 1: 27)
  - Vedemaier (Wedemeyer), General, 1946 (Folder 1: 28)
  - Vonsiatskii, Anastasii Andreevich, 1932 (Folder 1: 29)
  - Vorobchuk, A., 1950 (Folder 1: 30)
- Subject file, 1926-1970 and undated.
  Bulletins, certificates, circulars, clippings, correspondence, minutes, orders, pamphlets, reports, and statutes, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Bratstvo russkoi pravdy, 1926-1970 and undated.; See also Correspondence/Bratstvo russkoi pravdy
    - General
      - General, 1930 and undated (Folder 1: 31)
      - Certificates, 1930-1934 (Folder 1: 32)
      - Circulars, 1933-1935 and undated (Folder 1: 33)
      - Clippings, 1930-1959 and undated (Folder 1: 34)
      - Correspondence
        - 1926-1931 and undated (Folder 1: 35)
        - 1932-1939, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - Documents relating to Siberian section, 1930-1936 and undated. (Folder 2: 2)
        Includes correspondence and orders
      - Orders, 1928-1934 (Folder 2: 3)
      - Printed matter
        - Bulletins, 1930-1935 (Folder 2: 4)
        - "Biulleten' tsentra Bratstva russkoi pravdy v S.A.S.Sh.,", 1931-1932 (Folder 2: 5)
        - Bound volume of various publications, 1926-193 and undated. (Folder 2: 6)
          Includes Russkaia Pravda, and Viestnik dal'nevostochnogo Bratstva russkoi pravdy
      - Reports, 1931-1935 and undated (Folder 2: 7)
    - "Bratsakaia informatsiia,", 1932-1933 (Folder 2: 8)
    - "Kratkaia istoricheskaia spravka,", undated. (Folder 2: 9)
      Holograph
    - "Polozhenie o verkhovnom kruge Bratstava russkoi pravdy,", 1933. (Folder 2: 10)
      Typescript
    - "Predatel'stvo i zagovor v BRP i moi ukhod,", 1932 (Folder 2: 11)
    - Verkhovnyi krug (Folder 2: 12)
  - Ioann (Maksimovich), Archbishop. Pamphlets, 1966; 1971 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Russians--Shanghai, China, 1937-1973 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Russians--Tubabao, Philippines, 1951-1952 and undated (Folder 2: 15)
  - Russkoe obshchestvo vzaimnogo kredita (Box 3)
    - General, 1935-1945 and undated (Folder 3: 1)
    - Clippings, 1936-1947 and undated (Folder 3: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1946 and undated. (Folder 3: 3)
      Includes letter from Archbishop Ioann (Maksimovich)
    - Minutes, 1939; 1948 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Reports, 1938-1940 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Statutes, 1933-1941 and undated (Folder 3: 6)
- Photographs, 1922-1949 and undated
  - Bratstvo russkoi pravdy. (Folder 3: 7)
    Four prints
  - Russians in Far East, 1922-1949 and undated. (Folder 3: 8)
    Twelve prints, two clippings
- Oversize file, 1936. (Box 4)
  Zhiganov, Vladimir Daniilovich, Russkie v Shangkhaie, 1936. Printed copy. Not filmed